William Merrow

1118 Girard Street NW, Washington, DC 20009 – william.merrow@gmail.com – 603-568-0366 Portfolio: https://wmerrow.github.io/

Summary

Information designer with proven experience creating web-based data visualizations for nonprofit clients on a range of public policy issues. Ability to approach projects from technical, creative, and project management standpoints. High attention to detail. Passion for clear and effective charts.

Skills

data analysis data visualization UX/UI design project management communication

Tools

Adobe Illustrator Sketch R (ggplot2) Excel (VBA) Tableau HTML CSS

Education

Tufts University, B.A. 2011, *summa cum laude*, Phi Beta Kappa

Major: International Relations, Minor: Sociology; coursework in statistics and econometrics

School for International Training, Cochabamba, Bolivia, January to May 2010

Independent coursework:

Intermediate D3 for Data Visualization, Knight Center

Data Visualization with D3, Knight Center

Sketch 3: Mobile and Web Designs, Udemy

Front-end Web Developer Nanodegree, Udacity

Professional Experience

Data Analyst & Visualization Specialist

Graphicacy, Washington, DC September 2015 to present

- Lead design of web-based visualizations for major think tank and nonprofit clients, using Adobe Illustrator, Excel, Tableau, and R to create clear and compelling graphics, working with researchers to ensure visualization design clearly communicates results and accomplishes goals
- Design websites, using Sketch to create high quality wireframes and comps in a deadline-based environment
- Lead data analysis projects, using R and Excel to manipulate and analyze large public datasets
- Manage large projects (\$100k+), managing developers and communicating with client to ensure project success
- Develop content on data visualization best practices, creating data visualization style guides, leading workshops, and representing Graphicacy at conferences and events
- Contribute to business development and strategic planning, securing new clients and helping to grow business

Princeton in Latin America Fellow in Monitoring & Evaluation The DREAM Project, Cabarete, Dominican Republic August 2014 to August 2015

- Led redesign, migration, and adoption of Salesforce database, creating objects, workflows, reports, and dashboards, using Tableau to visualize student data
- Managed and analyzed student data to assess education programs, identifying trends and ensuring data quality
- Led basic to advanced Excel workshops for all staff; trained managers in use of Salesforce and Tableau
- Managed data and reporting for USAID grant, leading to perfect score on audit of data system

Special Assistant to the President & CEO

InterAction, Washington, DC August 2011 to August 2014

Language Skills:

Spanish - professional German - conversational

- Coordinated data and communications for \$1.5b food security pledge by 30 international NGOs; prepared data for use in remarks of President Obama and Secretary Clinton
- Authored remarks, blogs, and articles for CEO on range of international development topics; authored policy briefs, published in 2012 Reality of Aid report on the role of corporations in foreign aid; coordinated drafting, editing, and copyediting of 42 policy briefs for flagship publication
- Managed advocacy projects, analyzing legislative language and meeting with congressional staff; managed CEO-level taskforces on aid reform and corporations in international development
- Promoted to Senior Associate level (2012) and Coordinator level (2014); voted Best Team Player

Congressional Program Intern

Inter-American Dialogue, Washington, DC *June to August 2011*

Research Intern

Americans for Campaign Reform, Concord, NH *June to August 2010*